Summary

I have been deeply and exclusively involved in supporting and deploying enterprise infrastructure management and automation tools globally for nearly a decade with the HP automation suite - Server Automation, Operations Orchestration, Network Automation, Cloud Service Automation.

Transitioning from Support to Professional Services in March 2008, I continue to solve complex infrastructure problems: in repair, design, and implementation; keeping multiple projects running with multiple customers at the same time, on time; developing and implementing Best Practices in DCA; contributing to internal and external knowledge base articles and blog posts; supporting and delivering cloud infrastructure, management, and automation; conducting on-site engagement/project management; acting as primary PM liaison; writing and delivering project and environment documentation.

I have a diverse background across many fields – both technical and non-technical – and varied industries (medical devices, professional services, financial services, retail, health, non-profits, education, etc). I am comfortable on almost any platform, and have used every major one excepting mainframes (Linux, FreeBSD, Haiku (and BeOS), Mac OS X, Windows (server and desktop), Solaris, AIX). While delivering cloud and data center automation solutions, I have been exposed to the VMware product line (ESXi, vCenter, vSphere), Amazon AWS, and other cloud and virtualization platforms.

I have tutored, developed curriculum materials, written tutorials/how-tos, taught classes, provided mentoring, lead teams, and work effectively either independently or on a team.

Automation and Cloud Experience

Manager

pureIntegration

Professional Services / Cloud & Automation

Dec 2015 - present

Herndon VA / Lily KY

- Deliver cloud and automation solutions (HP SA, OO, NA, CSA)
- Mentor and train colleagues and customers in HP automation tools
- Onsite and remote customer project management
- Team coordination and project management for customer engagements Industry sectors:
 - o eCommerce
 - Telecommunications
 - Internal product development

Senior Technical Consultant

Intact Technology

Automation Practice Team Lead Greenbelt MD / Lexington KY Oct 2014 - Dec 2015

- Mentor and train other consultants in HP automation suite tools (SA, OO, CSA)
- Co-develop presales demos and presentations for internal and external use
- Provide demos and presentations of automation tools for sales & management staff
- Deliver PoC, Pilot, and Production implementations of automation initiatives
 Industry sector sampling
 - o Government agencies
 - Financial services
 - o IT service providers

Solutions Architect

Avnet (formerly Seamless)

Cloud and Data Center Automation team

Jul 2013 - Sep 2014

Phoenix AZ / Lexington KY

Purchased by Avnet in Jul 2013 as a resource and human capital acquisition

Solutions Architect

Seamless Technologies (acquired by Avnet)

Business Technology Optimization

Aug 2012 - Jun 2013

Morristown NJ / Lexington KY

 Architected and delivered cloud and automation solutions across industry sectors and customer types

Industry sector sampling:

- o Medical devices and products
- Real estate management
- o Health care services
- Insurance providers
- Power utilities

Senior Solutions Engineer

Seamless Technologies (acquired by Avnet)

Business Technology Optimization

Feb 2011 - Aug 2012

Morristown NJ / Lexington KY

 Delivered automation and cloud solutions for a wide variety of customers across industry sectors

Industry sector sampling

- o Pharmaceuticals
- o Financial services
- o IT service providers
- Dot com eBusinesses
- Health information processing

Solutions Architect

Regan Technologies

Data Center Automation & Consolidation

Jan 2010 - Feb 2011'

Wallingford CT / Lexington KY

- Provide in-depth system architecting and implementation experience surrounding:
 - o HP's BSA (Business Service Automation) suite for Data Center Automation
 - o Server Automation
 - o Operations Orchestrator
 - o Network Automation
 - BSA Essentials
 - Business process management
 - o Network and systems monitoring
- Tied disparate partner technologies with customer needs, inside budgets, exceeding expectations
- Acted as single point of contact / escalation point for support of customer-deployed automation tools while engaged in project work
- Trained users with automation tools through one-on-one mentoring and group lunches
- Guide customers through technological change utilizing:
 - Automation
 - Consolidation
 - Virtualization
- Primary customer engagements
 - o Aetna (Hartford/Middletown CT)
 - o HealthQuest (Poughkeepsie NY)
 - Staples (Framingham MA)

Warren Myers +1 859 550 0420

Assistant Vice President (contract)

Barclays Capital

Data Center Automation

Jun 2009 – Dec 2009

Singapore

- Supervised global implementation of HP Server Automation for Barclays Capital in support of infrastructure management initiatives
- Developed support, disaster recovery, and escalation documentation and procedures surrounding the automation platform
- Trained global users and support staff on effective use of HPSA

Technical Consultant

Hewlett Packard

HP Server Automation

Mar 2008 - Apr 2009

Cary NC

- Provided onsite expertise for our Server Automation product line
- Installation, troubleshooting, architecting all aspects of post-sales processing
- Global deployment of HPSA 7.5 and SAR 7.5 for HSBC (US, UK, Hong Kong)
- Deployment of HPSA 7.0 for Home Depot
- Maintained ProServe-Support handoff documentation for HPSA deployments

Technical Solutions Consultant

Hewlett Packard

(formerly Opsware)

HP Server Automation

Nov 2007 - Mar 2008

Cary NC

Customer Support Engineer

Opsware (acquired by HP) Jan 2007 - Oct 2007

Opsware SAS|NAS|PAS

Cary NC

- Provided in-depth, advanced phone and e-mail technical support for HP/Opsware's enterprise management tool, Server Automation System
- Frontline support of Network Automation System and Process Automation System (through Jul '07)
- Maintained current overview of all open customer issues to track "common" problems, and keep related support cases together
- Culled support case information into both internal and external knowledge base articles

Featured Published Articles

Debugging and Supporting Software Systems (eBook)

http://cnx.org/content/col11350/latest

Automating or Automation?

http://antipaucity.com/?p=1985

What to Automate

http://antipaucity.com/?p=1331

Delivering Solutions - "Shipping is a Feature!"

http://antipaucity.com/?p=1341

Storage Series (bind mounts, technologies, and an allocation approach)

http://antipaucity.com/?p=1145

http://antipaucity.com/?p=1152

http://antipaucity.com/?p=1154

http://antipaucity.com/?p=1157

http://antipaucity.com/?p=1161

Why Technical Intricacies Matter

http://antipaucity.com/?p=984

Virtualization Myth - Reduction of Servers

http://antipaucity.com/?p=869

Unsales

http://antipaucity.com/?p=2148

Queuing the Next Generation

http://antipaucity.com/?p=103

Why Do Current Graphical User Interfaces Not Work Naturally & How They Can Be Fixed?

http://ubiquity.acm.org/article.cfm?id=1086454

Education

2006: BA Computer Information Systems Elon University Sep 03 – Dec 06

Member Association for Computing Machinery

Treasurer o5-o6 academic year; Assistant Treasurer fall o6

Published "Why Do Current Graphical User Interfaces Not Work Naturally & How They Can Be Fixed?" ACM Ubiquity

2001: AAS Computer Information Systems Hudson Valley CC Sep 99 – May 01

Proficiencies

Management Tools:

Hewlett Packard Data Center Automation suite

Server Automation - Advanced

Operations Orchestration - Intermediate

Network Automation - Familiar

Cloud Service Automation - Intermediate

Open source configuration automation, management, and orchestration

Ansible - Familiar

Cfengine - Familiar

Chef - Familiar

Puppet - Familiar

Linux:

Intermediate administration of Red Hat/CentOS

Familiar with several other distributions

Mac OS X:

Intermediate

Virtualization and Cloud Platforms:

VMware - Intermediate administration and usage of vCenter, ESXi, vSphere

Digital Ocean - Familiar with both manual and API-based VM deployments

AWS - Familiar

Windows:

Intermediate administration: Server 2012, 2008, 2003, XP Pro, 7, 10

Languages:

Familiar with several scripting languages

Organization Involvement

Bluegrass Linux User Group – member and occasional presenter http://bglug.net Lex>>Fwd – co-organizer and occasional presenter http://lexfwd.tk

References

http://linkedin.com/in/warrenmyers http://antipaucity.com/category/technical http://careers.stackoverflow.com/warrenmyers

Prior Experience

System Administration Intern Shodor Education Foundation

System Maintenance, Apprentice Mentoring

Jun 2006 – Jan 2007

Durham NC

• Assisted in the maintenance of a heterogeneous network of Linux, Mac, and Windows machines

- Developed web sites and curriculum information for workshops taught at Shodor
- Taught/assisted with various workshops
- Developed time- and cost-saving measures to increase the efficiency of the organization, including system maintenance scripts
- Created portable lab-on-CD (Shodonix, based on Knoppix)

Assistant Systems Administrator Elon Univerity
Linux, Unix, VMware, Windows Jan 2005 – Dec 2006

Elon NC

User account creation/maintenance

- General system maintenance & data backup
- Researched anti-spam solution summer 'o6 (Barracuda Networks vs IronPort), saving the school circa \$25k in the first year, and nearly \$60k over the next 4 years by implementing Barracuda's solution

TIS Intern Sigma Xi

Efficiency Improvements Jun 2005 – May 2006

RTP NC

 Wrote utility scripts to update website to incorporate direct access to member database to provide better security for members and easier data maintenance

Programs Intern Sigma Xi

Outreach Programs Oct 2004 - May 2005

RTP NC

- Managed science educator volunteer database
- Worked on computational science education website
- Assisted Sally Ride TOYchallenge eastern finals 2 years in a row organizing volunteers and activities
- Worked with document management and sharing tools from Rice University's Connexions (http://cnx.org) project with UNSEG project on climate change

Research Apprentice Shodor Education Foundation

Math & Science Educational Workshops Oct 2003 – Sep 2004

Durham NC

- Developed computational science curriculum materials
- Maintained, updated, and wrote educational applets in Java
- Created and maintained various web sites
- Built utility scripts in PHP and bash
- Taught student workshops in math and science

PC Support TechnicianElon UniversityStudent, Staff, & Faculty System CareNov 2003 - May 2004

Elon NC

Vehicle Service AttendantHertz Rent-A-CarVehicle PreparationSep 2000 - May 2003

Latham NY

High Temperature Superconductor InternIntermagnetics GeneralTechnology DevelopmentJun 1998 – Apr 1999

Latham NY

- Developed quality analysis tests for manufacturing processes
- Enhanced data acquisition methods, improving data collection & reporting using LabVIEW & Excel
- HTS-LTS downleads for CERN Large Hadron Collider
- General Atomics / Los Alamos National Labs HTS Fault Current Limiter